Guide to the Office of Planning Information and Policy Analysis records, 1898-2008.
Office of Planning Information and Policy Analysis records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Office of Planning Information and Policy Analysis records, 1898-2008.
4-8-3794
Cornell University.Office of Planning Information and Policy Analysis
26.5 cubic feet.
Financial Records, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Budget reports (1952-2008); graduate school reports; Operating Plans (1965-2002); fact books; various other surveys and financial reports, and e-Cornell files (1997-2003), compiled by Michael Whalen, Director of the Office of Planning Information and Policy Analysis.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Office of Planning Information and Policy Analysis is in the Division of Planning and Budget.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Budget reports (1952-2008); graduate school reports; Operating Plans (1965-2002); fact books; various other surveys and financial reports, and e-Cornell files (1997-2003), compiled by Michael Whalen, Director of the Office of Planning Information and Policy Analysis.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Whalen, Michael L.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Finance.; Cornell University--Planning.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 1-15 are restricted to permission of the office of origin.
CONTAINER LIST
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1952-1953 thru 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1964-1965; 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1974-1975; 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1979-1980 thru 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1982-1983; 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1986-1988 thru 1990-1991 (Box 6)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1989-1990 thru 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1992-1993 thru 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1995-1996; 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 1999-2000 thru 2001-2002 (Box 11)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 2003-2004 thru 2005-2006 (Box 12)
  - Cornell University Budgets, 2006-2007 thru 2007-2008 (Box 13)
  - Monthly Investments, 1968-2001 (Box 14)
  - Monthly Investments, 2002-2008 (Box 15)
  - Gift Reports, 1943-2002 (Box 15)
  - Cornell University Financial Plan and Reports, 2002-2003; 2007-2008 (Box 16)
  - Cornell University Operating Plan, 1991-1992 thru 2001-2002 (Box 17)
  - Graduate School Reports, 1953-1990 (Box 18)
  - Graduate School Reports, 1990-2003 (Box 19)
  - Cornell University Research Reports, 1949-1969 (Box 19)
  - Cornell University Research Reports, 1970-2002 (Box 20)
  - Cornell University Responsibility Center Analysis, 1973-1990 (Box 20)
  - Fact Books: (Box 20)
    - a. Endowed and Statutory, January 1978 (Box 20)
      - 1. Cornell University, October 1979 (Box 20)
      - 2. Cornell University, November 1980 (Box 20)
      - Facts- (Brochure), 2005-2006 (Box 21)
  - Fact Books continued: (Box 21)
    - a. Endowed Colleges, Fall 1977 (Box 21)
    - b. Endowed and Statutory Colleges, 1978 (Box 21)
  - Books: (Box 21)
    - a. Cornell University Institutional Profile, 1983 (Box 21)
    - b. Cornell University Institutional Profile, 1986 (Box 21)
    - c. Financial Arrangements for Accessory Instruction, May 1977 (Box 21)
    - d. On the Business of Being a University, 1990-1991 (Box 21)
    - e. Alternative Contexts for Planning Cornell's Future, Ian R. Stewart, 1977 (Box 21)
    - f. Comparable Institutional Data (Box 21)
    - g. Survey and Observations, April 1973 (Box 21)
    - h. Survey and Observations, June 1974 (Box 21)
    - i. Survey and Observations, June 1975 (Box 21)
    - j. Statistical Profile of Recent Financial Trends, October 1980 (Box 21)
    - k. Statistical Profile of Recent Financial Trends, January 1981 (Box 21)
    - l. Accessory Instruction - Analysis and Recommendations, 1993-1994 (Box 21)
    - m. A Generation of Cornell, Jacob Gould Schurman, 1898 (Box 21)
    - n. Changes in Financial Condition and Outlook, 1974-1977; February 1978 (Box 21)
    - o. Financial Profile, October 1977 (Box 21)
    - p. Cornell in the Seventies, May 1973 (Box 21)
    - q. Dale R. Corson Report to the Trustees, March 1978 (Box 21)
    - r. Employee Growth Studies, 1976-1988 (Box 21)
    - s. University Information, 1972-1973 thru 1981-1982; April 1982 (Box 21)
    - t. Programs and Financial Information, June 1982 (Box 21)
  - Reports: (Box 22)
    - a. Ten Year Financial Report, 1937-1947; 1947-1950 (Box 22)
    - b. Memorial Statements, CU Faculty Index, 2nd Edition by Julian C. Smith, 1868-1990 (Box 22)
    - c. Cornell in the Seventies - Comments, 1972-1973 (Box 22)
    - d. Report of the Trustee Ad Hoc Committee on Financial Planning, September 1972 (Box 22)
    - e. The 10th Decade, 1968 (Box 22)
    - f. Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Minorities, October 1975 (Box 22)
    - g. Factual Profile of Cornell University, 1944-1975 (Box 22)
    - h. Factual Profile of Cornell University, 1944-1971 (Box 22)
    - i. Priorities Study, June 1975 (Box 22)
    - j. Academic Appointments; Dean of Faculty, 1969-1970 thru 1982-1983 (Box 22)
    - k. Cornell University Survey of Administration Management, Vol. 3 of 5, Student Affairs (Box 22)
    - l. Accounting for the Full Cost of Research, A Study of Indirect Costs (Box 22)
    - m. Endowed Ithaca Model for Long-Range Financial Planning, June 1973 (Box 22)
    - n. Cornell in the Seventies, April 1973 (Box 22)
    - o. Cornell in the Seventies, Goals, Priorities, and Plans; Background Information and Studies, Appendix, May 1973 (Box 22)
    - p. Study of Rising Costs at 10 Universities, September 1967 (Box 22)
    - q. Cornell University - Report of the Director of Priorities Study to Dale Corson, June 27, 1975 (Box 22)
    - r. Report to Ad Hoc Committee on Capital Financing (Box 22)
    - s. Changes in Financial Condition and Outlook, 1974-1977 (Box 22)
    - t. Updating Analysis of Trustee and Ad Hoc Committee, February 1978 (Box 22)
    - u. Capital Program and Analysis of Capital Resources and Needs (Box 22)
    - v. 1977-1981 Endowed Colleges at Ithaca, May 1977 (Box 22)
  - Cornell University Operating Plan, 1965-1966 thru 1976-1977 (Box 23)
  - Cornell University Operating Plan, 1977-1978 thru 1983-1984 (Box 24)
  - Cornell University Operating Plan, 1984-1985 thru 1990-1991 (Box 25)
  - E-Cornell and Distance Learning Files, 1997-2008 (Box 26)
  - Distance Learning Documents, Reports, Cornell/Foundation House Mission Statement, Will Medical College, 1997-1999 (Box 27)
  - Distance Learning Activities at: Brown, Columbia, Dartmouth, Harvard, MIT, University of Pennsylvania, Princeton, Stanford, Ylae, University of California, 1997-1999 (Box 27)
  - Jackson Hole Retreat (Box 27)